Gas cylinders are an important part of homes
.  There are very few people who do not use gas cylinders in their homes
.  In some cases,
damage can occur due to gas cylinders
.  If that
happens, you
will get coverage of up to Rs 50 lakh.  Petroleum companies like Indian
Oil, Hindustan Petroleum, and Bharat
Petroleum
have this insurance policy.
Insurance claims can be made for accidents, property damage, and death caused by gas cylinders.
This insurance, which currently has an LPG connection, is
provided through ICICI Lombard.  LPG cylinders have
an expiration date.
The insurance of an LPG cylinder is linked to its purchase date and expiry
date
.  Therefore, accidents
caused by a cylinder that has passed its expiration date are
not covered by this insurance.  Therefore, it is important to pay attention to the
expiration date when using the cylinder
.
Using a connection in someone else's name is also a reason for not getting insurance
.  Only
individuals who have registered the cylinder will
receive the insurance amount.
Also, it is not possible to put a nominee in this
.  Therefore, if
the person to whom the cylinder is registered
dies in an accident, a claim
cannot be made.  The maximum amount of compensation for
an accident caused by an LPG gas cylinder is
up to Rs 50 lakh.
This is available after deaths occur in accidents.  The maximum one person can
get is that lakh.  In
case of damage to customers' property,
insurance claims can be made up to a maximum of Rs. 1 lakh
.
In case of injury, a maximum claim of Rs. 30 lakh can be made
.  Also,
a person can only get a maximum of ₹2 lakh
.  Each person will also
receive emergency assistance of up to Rs. 25,000.  Each person affected by such an accident will
receive a maximum compensation of Rs. 10 lakh.  A
maximum of Rs 15 lakh will be available for the treatment of family members
.  If an accident occurs due to a gas cylinder, the
nearest police
station or distributor must
be notified within 30 days of the accident.  After that, you can apply for claim
proceedings by providing a copy of the FIR and
details of those injured or deceased in the accident
.  In addition,
details of the condition of the injured and treatment costs must also
be submitted.  The information
will be evaluated by the agency and the insurance company.   The
gas companies will send the insurance proceeds
to the distributor.  The supplier
will transfer the claim money to the customer.  It takes
three to five months to receive this amount
.  Become a
part of this project only after understanding more details about it.